Hello English letters, welcome to English
Pod. My name is Marko, and I'm Erica.
We're bringing you a great
elementary podcast today.
That's right. And we're going to
be teaching you how to order pizza.
Yeah, you know, pizza is one of my favorite
foods and the favorite food of many people.
Exactly, it's one of those
common foods that you're
at home and you want
to order something to eat.
And the typical thing is pizza.
Yeah, but you know, there's
some very special language
that you've got to use
and you've got to know
this language when
you want to order a pizza.
Exactly. So let's listen
to this dialogue for
the first time as a
man is ordering pizza.
Good evening, pizza host. This is
Marty's speaking. May I take your order?
Yes, I'd like a medium pizza with
pepperoni olives and extra cheese.
We have a two for one
special on large pizzas.
Would you like a
large pizza instead?
Sure, that sounds good.
Great. Would you like your
second pizza to be the
same size as the first?
No. Make the second
one with ham, pineapple,
and green peppers.
Oh, and make it 10 crust.
Okay, then crust. Your
total is 2150 and your
order will arrive in
30 minutes or it's free.
Perfect. Thank you. Bye.
Sure, wait. I need your address.
Okay, so I guess he's not getting his
pizza. No, he forgot to give his address.
That's a bit of a problem.
Okay, let's take a look
at some of the vocabulary
in language takeaway.
Language takeaway. All right, we've
got some great pizza words for you today.
And the first one we
have is a medium pizza.
Medium pizza. So
that's the size, right?
Yeah. Medium. You can
say medium or 12 inch?
12 inch. Usually a
medium pizza is 12 inches.
Yeah, so you could say
I'd like a 12 inch pizza.
Okay, for those of us
who use centimeters,
this would be more or
less 30 centimeters. Okay.
All right, let's take a
look at the next size,
a large pizza, a large pizza. So it might
also be called an 18 inch. 18 inch pizza,
or isn't it sometimes
called a family size?
Maybe family size. I guess it
depends where you're ordering.
Yeah. Okay, so large
and medium pizzas.
Now let's take a look at
some of the ingredients.
Yes. Okay, we have pepperoni,
pepperoni, pepperoni.
This is the common
ingredient in all pizza.
It's my favorite. A pizza
is not a pizza unless
it has pepperoni. Okay,
so pepperoni is like,
is sausage, right?
Yeah, it's a little bit spicy,
a little bit spicy, and
they look like, like,
circles, red circles.
Yeah. Okay. Olives. Olives.
Olives. Olives are little
black or green balls.
Yes, little green
or black balls.
You can also find them in
a martini. Yeah, exactly. Yep.
It's very common for them
to have it's very common
to have an it's very common
to have an olive in a martini.
Yeah. Okay, and he also
ordered extra cheese.
Extra cheese. So that
means more cheese.
Extra. All right, another ingredient, ham,
ham, the meat of a pig. Yeah, ham. Yeah.
Okay, and he also ordered
another strange ingredient for
a pizza pineapple pineapple
pineapple pineapple.
Now, this is a fruit. I know,
so weird pineapple on a pizza.
Many people like
pineapple on on their pizza.
It's a tropical fruit.
Yeah, comes from Hawaii.
Usually, and it kind of looks
like a little palm
tree at the top.
Yeah, like, yeah, the top of
a pineapple looks like a tree.
So pineapple. Yep.
All right. Now, the last
description of a pizza, he
ordered it with thin crust.
Thin crust. Thin
crust. Thin crust.
Now, we know thin is some
skinny, but crust. What is crust?
It's the bread part of the
pizza. The outside part.
Yeah. Okay, so that's the
crust. That's my favorite
part of the food. Really?
Yeah. Thin crust or thick crust?
Thin crust. Yeah, thin crust.
And I just, I really love that bread
part. It's so important to a good pizza.
Okay, well, you
know, they also have,
they also have the
crust filled with cheese.
You know, it's so wrong.
That's good too. No.
All right, let's listen to
our dialogue again, and
then we'll come back
and talk a little bit more.
Good evening, pizza house. This is
Marty speaking. May I take your order?
Um, yes, I'd like a medium pizza with
pepperoni, olives, and extra cheese.
We have a two-for-one
special on large pizzas.
Would you like a
large pizza instead?
Sure. That sounds good.
Great. Would you like
your second pizza to
be the same as the first?
No. Make the second
one with ham, pineapple,
and green peppers. Oh,
and make it thin crust.
Okay. Thin crust. Your
total is 2150, and your
order will arrive in
30 minutes, or it's free.
Perfect. Thank you. Bye. Sir.
Wait. I need your address.
Okay. Now we have
some really polite language
that you could use,
possibly with customers,
or with clients. Yep. Okay. So let's
take a look at them in fluency builder.
Fluency builder. Okay. All right. The first
phrase we have, um, I think is my favorite.
Uh, this is the way that Marty
answered the phone, right?
Mm-hmm. He said,
this is Marty speaking.
This is Marty speaking. This is Marty
speaking. Now, why is this so important?
Because a lot of people,
when they answer the
phone, say, "I'm Erica."
Like, "Hello, I'm Erica.
" Mm-hmm. Which is not what
English people say. Mm-hmm.
We always say, "Erika speaking."
Mm-hmm. This is Erica speaking.
Exactly. So guys, remember this.
You'll sound really, really great
when you use this on the phone.
This is Marty speaking. Exactly.
This is Marty. Well, don't
use Marty. Use your name.
All right. Then you also
mentioned a two-for-one
special, two-for-one
special, a two-for-one special.
So that means you're getting two pizzas,
right, for the price of one. Mm-hmm.
And a special is just a special promotion.
A special price. Special price. Yes.
Two-for-one special.
All right. All right.
Now a very easy phrase.
Mm-hmm. Would you like?
Would you like? Would
you like? Would you like?
Now this is a great
way to offer something.
It's a more polite way of asking.
Do you want? Do you want? Mm-hmm.
Do you want is
okay? Yeah, it's fine.
But it's less polite than
would you like? Exactly.
So whenever you offer
something, would you like
a cup of coffee? Would
you like to sit down?
Okay. Yep. So would
you like? Let's listen to our
dialogue for the last
time and then we'll come
back and talk about
pizza from a pizza expert.
Good evening. Pizza house.
This is Marty's speaking.
May I take your order? Yes.
I'd like a medium pizza with
pepperoni, olive, and extra cheese.
We have a two-for-one
special on large pizzas.
Would you like a large
pizza instead? Sure.
That sounds good. Great.
Would you like your second
pizza to be the same size as the first? No.
Make the second one with ham, pineapple,
and green peppers. Oh,
and make it 10 crust. Okay.
Then crust. Your total
is 2150 and your order
will arrive in 30 minutes
or it's free. Perfect.
Thank you, bye. Sure.
Wait. I need your address.
All right. We're back and we
are here with our pizza expert.
Who else but Marco
from Italian pod?
Hi, everyone. Marco
two, right? Marco one.
I am Marco zero. He is Marco one.
Yes. We've come to an agreement.
So zero. What's
the deal about this?
Well, we're talking about
pizza today and we wanted to
know what's your opinion since
pizza comes from Italy, right?
Well, thanks for
the question. First,
Marco zero. Is my mic
working? It should be.
Okay. So the problem
with pizza is that yes,
it comes from Italy, originated.
The story goes with an alright. Right,
put into the Regina
Margarita. But the problem
is that now this confusion
worldwide, pizza and
pizza, hot American
pizza, Italian pizza, that
is not the same thing.
It's not the same. Okay.
So pizza hut is in Italian pizza. No, no.
Oh my god. So the, okay. Here it goes.
Italian's a little bit.
Italian's make food,
but they're not good
at branding it. Okay.
America's a very
good at branding food.
So they have Starbucks and
Pizza Hut and blah, blah, blah.
The problem is that since they have to
brand it, they don't change their name.
So they do this pizza hut.
It's totally different from Italian pizza.
Wow. How is it different?
Have you ever seen
the two of them? Have
you ever compared them?
Yeah. They are very
different. That's true.
So, okay. Can you put
pineapple and ham on a pizza?
Technically, you could like it's possible.
As long as you call it Hawaiian,
you can put pineapple
in everything, I guess.
But the problem, what
I'm trying to say is that,
okay, Italian pizza is,
you know, you have the,
the flowers, the past,
the pasta, the pizza,
the crust, the crust, the tomato
sauce, and then the McDonald's.
And that's the basic.
And then you can do it on
top of it with some variation.
American pizza is basically
take everything that
you have on the
table and put it on it.
That's the main difference.
But I'm not saying I'm against
the American pizza. I'm
saying that you just should
change the name
to another thing.
What do you suggest? We
should call it? Zippa. Zippa.
It's close enough.
Close enough. Yeah.
You know, but you need
like an a zippa. A zippa.
To indicate that it's American.
A for America. Maybe.
A dot zippa. A dot zippa
dot com. Can I have a a zippa.
So, Margot, a zippa
pod dot com. So, Margot,
I know that, um, that you are
very much against having pizza.
Pizza. Um, I like it as, uh, as an
exotic experience, because I like the fact
that it's so much stuff
in it that you cannot
even tell the difference
between the ingredients.
You know, they,
they have the super,
mega, super, super, super, super,
super, with cheese in the crust.
I don't even know what's inside.
Yeah. It's great. It's
great. It's like there's
a party in my mouth
and everybody's invited.
That's for me the
feeling of America.
Well, another interesting
thing when we were eating with
pizza with Marco is
that you notice the way
that people from
different countries eat pizza.
That's right. It's how young
people fold their pizza.
We do fold it. And
another thing is that we
have a whole pizza.
Like if I order one pizza,
it's not like I share everybody
as a one, uh, slice of it.
We order one pizza, you order your pizza,
you order her pizza, and so on. Pizza is
personal. Pizza is a person.
Don't mess with my pizza, Marcus.
All right. Well,
this whole pizza
discussion, let's see what our
listeners have to say about it.
I know that we
have listeners from
all over the world. And what
do they do with their pizzas?
Yes. What are their
zipas or their zipas?
What do you like on
your pizza? Exactly.
For example, I don't
hide you on the crust to be
then how high I know
that for example, you want
your crust to be another,
for example, in some
countries, they put
ketchup on their pizza.
I know once I was eating
pizza, like I had a Japanese
friend who ordered a
pizza from Pizza Hut.
And the pizza had the
pineapple and other stuff on it.
And then she took out
like ketchup in Mayonnaise.
Oh, no. Like wild. Although I must
tell you, I like to basket one my pizza.
And I know that's wrong. I
know. I'm sorry. But I like it.
Yeah. You know, what
you have to do, Erica,
then, you know, history
will judge your pizza.
All right, we better go.
We're out of time and
before Marco has a heart
attack or an aneurysm or
something, we're
making a manger here.
And if you have any questions
for us and also for Marco,
because I'm sure he's going to
be commenting on this aspect.
Sure. So go to our comment
section at englishpot.
com. And Marco and I are Marco zero and I
are always there to answer your questions.
All right, everyone.
We'll see you there. Goodbye. Bye.